<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jerry Lin</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jerry Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Al Dente Restaurant Finder</title>
      <link>/projects/aldente/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/aldente/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the ideal consistency of pasta — &amp;ldquo;to the tooth&amp;rdquo; — this mighty restaurant finder makes it easier than ever to find the restaurant that&amp;rsquo;s perfect for you. Simply type in a search term, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find results curated by Yelp&amp;rsquo;s search engine. If you&amp;rsquo;re paralyzed by indecision, use the convenient Quick Recommendations panel for ideas. With automated location access, you can skip the hassle of typing in your location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DMV Buster</title>
      <link>/projects/dmvbuster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/dmvbuster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a college student trying to grab an appointment for a behind-the-wheel test. Unfortunately, appointments are literally booked out three months in advance. There are occasional openings when someone cancels, but these are hard to find and usually snatched up instantly. I went looking for bots online to automate this appointment search for me, but none of them work ever since the DMV deployed a ReCaptcha on the appointment finder page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation Apps Make Traffic Worse for Everyone</title>
      <link>/research/navigationapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/navigationapp/</guid>
      <description>Navigation apps like Waze claim to &amp;ldquo;outsmart traffic and get everyone the best route.&amp;rdquo; But what happens when everyone&amp;rsquo;s using these apps at the same time? In all kinds of cities across America, navigation apps have sent hordes of drivers down local streets not meant for such levels of traffic, endangering residents and increasing congestion.
In this paper, I attempt to empirically confirm this affect of app-induced congestion on local streets by analyzing data and quantifying the increase in travel times on local streets due to cut-through traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Coal, No Revenue, One Employee: Inside UChicago Trustee’s “$1.7 Billion” Firm</title>
      <link>/clips/stevanovich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clips/stevanovich/</guid>
      <description>Documents reveal that UChicago trustee Steve Stevanovich is late on over \$12 million in pledges to the University, and that by overselling his aviation company he may have committed securities fraud.
Notes: Our investigation was profiled by Felix Salmon from Axios, who called it “fantastic.” Our article was cited in federal bankruptcy court.
The almost 5,000-word investigative piece required reading over 1,000 pages of documents. I also coded a special site to host the article and designed the featured graphic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking Perceptions of Data-Driven Inferences Underlying Online Targeting and Personalization</title>
      <link>/publications/tracking-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/tracking-transparency/</guid>
      <description>Claire Dolin, Ben Weinshel, Shawn Shan, Chang Min Hahn, Euirim Choi, Michelle L. Mazurek, Blase Ur
Much of what a user sees browsing the internet, from ads to search results, is targeted or personalized by algorithms that have made inferences about that user. Prior work has documented that users find such targeting simultaneously useful and creepy. We begin unpacking these conflicted feelings through two online studies. In the first study, 306 participants saw one of ten explanations for why they received an ad, reflecting prevalent methods of targeting based on demographics, interests, and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pearsons, Who Pledged $100 Million to UChicago, Want Their Money Back</title>
      <link>/clips/pearson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clips/pearson/</guid>
      <description>Sensitive documents obtained by The Maroon last summer and a new lawsuit reveal a strained relationship between the University of Chicago and the Pearson family, calling the future of the Pearson Institute, which was supposed to change the world, into question.
Notes: I broke this story, catching Chicago media outlets by surprise, possibly because the lawsuit was filed in a district court in Oklahoma—not in Illinois. The article was cited on Page A2 of The Wall Street Journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Bannon Accepts Invitation to Speak at the University of Chicago</title>
      <link>/clips/bannon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clips/bannon/</guid>
      <description>Booth professor Luigi Zingales, who is interested in populism, confirmed to The Maroon that Bannon accepted his invitation.
Note: I waited for two hours outside Professor Zingales’ office to confirm a tip that we received. We then published a story before every outlet, which would later be confirmed by the Chicago Sun-Times and the Chicago Tribune. The Washington Post wrote about the invitation as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Hospital Patient Information Was Potentially Vulnerable to Hackers</title>
      <link>/clips/printers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clips/printers/</guid>
      <description>A Maroon investigation found that weaknesses in the University’s network could have allowed hackers to steal sensitive information from networked printers, as well as access and, in some cases, control cameras and other connected devices.
Notes: The Illinois Collegiate Press Association said that this was 2017’s best news story in Illinois at the university level. The article won in the large school (4,000+ students) non-dailies category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Inside Look at the University’s Budget</title>
      <link>/clips/university-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clips/university-budget/</guid>
      <description>Private administration documents shed light on strategic budget deficits and deliberations on how to control spending.
Notes: This article was part of a series that was deemed by the Illinois Collegiate Press Association as being 2017’s best in-depth reporting series at the university level. The series won in the large school (4,000+ students) non-dailies category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m a freshman at Duke who is interested in machine learning, data science, government, and transportation. In my free time, you might catch me reading a history book or playing quizbowl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>